<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cybersecurity on MarcoInTech</title>
    <link>/cybersecurity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cybersecurity on MarcoInTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SSH Authentication with Public Key: A Complete Guide</title>
      <link>/cybersecurity/ssh-authentication-guide-with-header/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cybersecurity/ssh-authentication-guide-with-header/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;SSH (Secure Shell) is a widely used protocol for securely accessing remote systems. One of the most secure and convenient ways to authenticate over SSH is through &lt;strong&gt;public key authentication&lt;/strong&gt;. This guide will show you how to generate an SSH key pair, set it up on a remote host, and cover important security considerations and how to mitigate risks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-ssh-public-key-authentication&#34;&gt;What Is SSH Public Key Authentication?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Instead of logging in with a username and password, public key authentication uses a &lt;strong&gt;pair of cryptographic keys&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell Execution Policies: Understanding and Managing Security</title>
      <link>/cybersecurity/ps_exc_policies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/cybersecurity/ps_exc_policies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-what-are-powershell-execution-policies&#34;&gt;🔹 What Are PowerShell Execution Policies?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell &lt;strong&gt;execution policies&lt;/strong&gt; are security measures that control how scripts run on a system. They help prevent unauthorized or malicious scripts from executing. However, they are &lt;strong&gt;not a security feature&lt;/strong&gt;—they are a safety measure designed to &lt;strong&gt;prevent accidental script execution&lt;/strong&gt; rather than block malicious code.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By default, execution policies are set to:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restricted&lt;/strong&gt; on Windows client systems (no scripts allowed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RemoteSigned&lt;/strong&gt; on Windows Server systems (scripts need a signature if downloaded)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To check the current execution policy on your machine, use the command:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
