<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT Support on MarcoInTech</title>
    <link>/tags/it-support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IT Support on MarcoInTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/it-support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reset Local Account Password From Advanced Startup Options</title>
      <link>/guides/reset-windows11-local-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/guides/reset-windows11-local-password/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-problem&#34;&gt;✅ Problem&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You’ve forgotten the password to your &lt;strong&gt;local account&lt;/strong&gt; on a Windows 11 PC and can’t log in. There’s no Microsoft account attached, no password reset disk, and you don’t want to use third-party tools. The only way remaining is to format the laptop. But no, stop there and read below!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-goal&#34;&gt;🎯 Goal&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Access the system and reset the password &lt;strong&gt;using only Windows built-in tools&lt;/strong&gt;, without reinstalling or losing any data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting Outlook: A Practical Guide for IT Support</title>
      <link>/troubleshooting/troubleshooting-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/troubleshooting/troubleshooting-outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Outlook stops working as expected, users are quick to reach out—and often under pressure. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s slow performance, sync issues, or complete failure to launch, diagnosing Outlook problems requires a methodical approach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guide outlines essential steps to troubleshoot Outlook, from basic checks to deeper diagnostic tools, helping you determine whether the root cause lies with the client, the server, or in between.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-checks&#34;&gt;Basic Checks&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Before diving into more advanced steps, start with a few quick validations:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Troubleshoot SCCM Client Issues</title>
      <link>/troubleshooting/troubleshoot-sccm-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/troubleshooting/troubleshoot-sccm-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-sccm&#34;&gt;What is SCCM?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SCCM (System Center Configuration Manager), now part of &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager&lt;/strong&gt;, is a systems management platform that enables IT administrators to manage large groups of Windows-based computers. It provides tools for:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Software deployment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Operating system imaging&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Patch management&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Inventory collection&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remote control&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SCCM relies on a local client agent installed on each managed machine. When the SCCM client fails, the device may stop receiving software updates, policies, or applications, and Software Center may not launch. This guide covers essential troubleshooting steps to restore client functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registry Value Types --&gt; What They Are and Why They Matter</title>
      <link>/guides/registry-value-types-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/guides/registry-value-types-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Windows Registry is a critical part of the operating system—a database that stores settings and options for Windows itself and all installed applications. Inside this system, every stored value has a &lt;strong&gt;type&lt;/strong&gt;, and that type determines how the data is interpreted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this guide, I’ll walk you through the most common &lt;strong&gt;Registry Value Types&lt;/strong&gt;, what they represent, when they’re used, and why they matter from both a configuration and security perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speed Up Your Windows 11 Laptop</title>
      <link>/troubleshooting/windows11-troubleshooting-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/troubleshooting/windows11-troubleshooting-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your computer feels slower than usual, don’t panic. In many cases, the issue isn’t hardware-related — it’s just background clutter, outdated files, or corrupted system components.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this guide, I’ll show you how to speed up your Windows 11 laptop using &lt;strong&gt;only built-in tools&lt;/strong&gt;, no third-party software required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-1-use-disk-cleanup&#34;&gt;🧹 1. Use Disk Cleanup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Windows includes a classic tool called &lt;strong&gt;Disk Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt; that helps remove temporary files and system junk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
