<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT Support on MarcoInTech</title>
    <link>/tags/it-support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IT Support on MarcoInTech</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/it-support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Troubleshoot SCCM Client Issues</title>
      <link>/troubleshooting/troubleshoot-sccm-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/troubleshooting/troubleshoot-sccm-client/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-to-troubleshoot-sccm-client-issues&#34;&gt;How to Troubleshoot SCCM Client Issues&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-sccm&#34;&gt;What is SCCM?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SCCM (System Center Configuration Manager), now part of &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Endpoint Configuration Manager&lt;/strong&gt;, is a systems management platform that enables IT administrators to manage large groups of Windows-based computers. It provides tools for:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Software deployment&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Operating system imaging&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Patch management&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Inventory collection&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remote control&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;SCCM relies on a local client agent installed on each managed machine. When the SCCM client fails, the device may stop receiving software updates, policies, or applications, and Software Center may not launch. This guide covers essential troubleshooting steps to restore client functionality.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Registry Value Types --&gt; What They Are and Why They Matter</title>
      <link>/guides/registry-value-types-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/guides/registry-value-types-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Windows Registry is a critical part of the operating system—a database that stores settings and options for Windows itself and all installed applications. Inside this system, every stored value has a &lt;strong&gt;type&lt;/strong&gt;, and that type determines how the data is interpreted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this guide, I’ll walk you through the most common &lt;strong&gt;Registry Value Types&lt;/strong&gt;, what they represent, when they’re used, and why they matter from both a configuration and security perspective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Speed Up Your Windows 11 Laptop</title>
      <link>/troubleshooting/windows11-troubleshooting-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/troubleshooting/windows11-troubleshooting-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If your computer feels slower than usual, don’t panic. In many cases, the issue isn’t hardware-related — it’s just background clutter, outdated files, or corrupted system components.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this guide, I’ll show you how to speed up your Windows 11 laptop using &lt;strong&gt;only built-in tools&lt;/strong&gt;, no third-party software required.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;-1-use-disk-cleanup&#34;&gt;🧹 1. Use Disk Cleanup&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Windows includes a classic tool called &lt;strong&gt;Disk Cleanup&lt;/strong&gt; that helps remove temporary files and system junk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
